# IFEDOLAPO AKANO

#### Accountant

Ibadan

dolleypeey4show@yahoo.ca

08085430091

Detail-oriented, efficient and organized professional with extensive experience in accounting systems. Possess strong analytical and problem solving skills, with the ability to make well thought out decisions. Excellent written and verbal communication skills. Highly trustworthy, discreet and ethical.



#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Account officer (Assistant)**

Dotun Dada & Co - Ibadan

February 2015 to February 2016

Analyse monthly department budgeting and accounting reports to maintain expenditure controls.

Prepares asset, liability, and capital account entries by compiling and analyzing account information.

Documents financial transactions by entering account information

Summarizes current financial status by collecting information; preparing balance sheet, profit and loss statement, and other reports.

Reconciles financial discrepancies by collecting and analyzing account information.

#### Store keeper /Accountant

Base one Enterprise - Ibadan

November 2008 to July 2012

- Operate 10-key calculators, typewriters, and copy machines to perform calculations and produce documents.
- Receive, record, and bank cash, checks, and vouchers.
- Code documents according to company procedures.
- Access computerized financial information to answer general questions as well as those related to specific accounts.
- Classify, record, and summarize numerical and financial data to compile and keep financial records, using journals and ledgers or computers.

#### Trainee/Attendant

Praise Computer Center - Ibadan

January 2005 to October 2008

Delivered improved customer services.

Safeguarding cash from sales, kept proper record of sales which led to accurate reporting of sales transaction.

Surfing the internet to get necessary information relating to the business



## **EDUCATION**

### **Higher National Diploma in Accounting**

**Yaba College of Technology - Lagos** February 2016 to February 2018

#### **National Diploma in Accounting**

The Polytechnic Ibadan - Ibadan October 2012 to November 2014



SKILLS

Analytical skills (4 years), Microsoft office (10+ years), Communication skills (5 years), Business administration (7 years), Call Handling (2 years), Customer service (4 years), Accounting Software Packages (Less than 1 year)



## **CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES**

### **Young African Leaders Initiative (4 Certification)**

July 2015 to Present

- 1. Creating and Maintaining Social Enterprises
- 2. Understanding Climate Change
- 3. Community Organizing for Action
- 4. Management Strategies for People and Resource